Contact

Florianópolis, Santa Catarina, Brasil +55 48 991118890 (Mobile) vmaciel.dev@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/vmaciel-dev (LinkedIn) experiencemanager.com.br (Blog)

Top Skills

Adobe Experience Manager Adobe CQ5 Java

Languages

Português (Native or Bilingual)
Inglês (Native or Bilingual)
Alemão (Elementary)

Certifications

Adobe Experience Manager Back-End Developer AEM Developer AEM Certified Developer Java Essential Training Java Advanced Training

Vinicius Maciel Silva

Technical Architect & Sr. AEM Certified Developer Florianópolis, Santa Catarina, Brazil

Summary

Vinicius is a recognised Adobe Certified Expert with work experience in development of marketing websites using AEM and integrating with Adobe Experience Cloud products. I also possess extensive experience in consulting, solution architecture and strategizing digital transformation, working with Adobe Partners throughout EMEA and LATAM markets

With more than 13 years as a knowledgeable and effective web technologies consultant with emphasis on Adobe & open-source web technologies and enterprise web content management systems (EWCMS).

Proficient in AEM for large scale Digital Projects, front-end component, template and dialog design. OSGi Backend Java Development, Servlets, OSGi bundles and components. AEM System Administration and Deployment.

Experience in software testing, TDD, BDD, Selenium, Mockito, JUnit. Solid experience in organising, building and documenting processes and evaluating tools.

Excellent knowledge of good practice around usability, maintainability and accessibility.

Experience

POSSIBLE Senior AEM developer July 2018 - Present Florianópolis, Santa Catarina

Avenue Code Adobe AEM consultant March 2017 - July 2018 (1 year 5 months) Belo Horizonte e Região, Brasil

POSSIBLE

AEM Developer

January 2016 - March 2017 (1 year 3 months)

Pelotas e Região, Brasil

Focused in developing applications integrated to Adobe Experience Manager (AEM 6.0), covering the full stack development from system design to frontend and backend development. Technologies involved are Java Servlets, Java Content Repository (JCR), Apache Sling, Apache Felix.

CONRAD CAINE GmbH

7 years

AEM Developer

February 2014 - January 2016 (2 years)

Front End Developer February 2013 - January 2014 (1 year)

ActionScript Developer February 2009 - January 2013 (4 years)

Universidade Federal de Pelotas ActionScript Developer January 2007 - February 2009 (2 years 2 months)

- Active development on Actionscript 3.0;
- Creation of multiple multimidia content for education on the mathematics field, content with audio, video, images, and mathematics samples especially on trigonometry area;
- Development of a video portal, containing all videos of the course to be watched by the students;
- Development of a video player chrome to be used inside the portal and embed on other platforms;
- Active development on Adobe Media Server and Red5, including download balance on the video streaming.

Education

Universidade Federal de Pelotas

Bachelor's degree, Ciência da Computação · (2006 - 2014)

IFSUL - Instituto Federal Sul-rio-grandense

Técnico, Gestão de Sistemas de Informação · (2004 - 2006)